[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
♪ ♪
[amoebas mooing]
[阿米巴原虫的叫声]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[laughs]
Yee-ha!
[笑]
呀哈！
Get along, little amoebas!
和睦相处吧，小阿米巴虫！
[amoebas mooing]
[阿米巴原虫的叫声]
[watch ticking]
[观察滴答声]
I did it!
我做到了！
It's sarsaparilla time!
现在是沙士时间！
[amoebas mooing]
[阿米巴原虫的叫声]
[grunts] Yah!
[buzzing]
[咕哝] 啊！
[嗡嗡声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
Holy osmosis!
神圣渗透！
I lived as an amoeba
for a whole week!
我像阿米巴原虫一样生活
整整一个星期！
[straining]
[紧张]
Hm.
Mm-hmm.
嗯。
嗯嗯。
[line trilling]
[行颤音]
- Can't get it to work,
- 无法让它工作，
can never get it to work!
[phone ringing]
永远无法让它发挥作用！
[电话铃声]
[yelling indistinctly]
- Hello?
[含糊不清地喊叫]
- 你好？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Karen, my Mainframe!
凯伦，我的主机！
I just made
a scientific breakthrough.
我刚刚做了
科学突破。
Let's go out
and celebrate, girl!
我们出去吧
庆祝吧，女孩！
- I'm sorry, Sandy.
I can't hear you
- 对不起，桑迪。
我听不到你说话
because someone can't shut up!
因为有人无法闭嘴！
- That's okay, Karen.
I'll tell you all about later.
- 没关系，凯伦。
稍后我会告诉你一切。
Let's meet up tonight
at the corner café!
今晚我们见面吧
在街角的咖啡馆！
- You got it, Bushy Tushy.
- 你明白了，布希·图希。
I will definitely be there.
我一定会在那里。
Okay, I'm off.
好吧，我走了。
- Those are not my test tubes!
-那些不是我的试管！
- Ugh.
- I don't know where
- 呃。
- 我不知道在哪里
they came from!
- Don't wait up.
他们来自！
- 别等了。
- [grunts]
[glass shatters]
- [咕哝]
[玻璃碎裂]
- [muttering excitedly]
Whoa.
- [兴奋地嘀咕]
哇哦。
- [sighs]
Don't forget to signal.
- [叹气]
别忘了打信号。
- Oh, thanks
for that Mrs. Puff, I--
-哦，谢谢
为了那位普芙夫人，我——
[phone rings]
[电话铃声]
- Hello?
- 你好？
- [grunts]
Howdy, Powder Puff!
- [咕哝]
你好，粉扑！
You wanna step out with me
and Karen tonight?
你想和我一起出去
今晚凯伦呢？
- Oh, yes, Sandy!
I desperately need to step out.
- 哦，是的，桑迪！
我迫切需要走出去。
[laughs]
- Ooh! You're talking to Sandy?
[笑]
- 哦！你在和桑迪说话吗？
Mrs. Puff, tell her
I said, "Hi!"
泡芙太太，告诉她
我说：“嗨！”
Tell her I said, "Hi!"
告诉她我说：“嗨！”
- We'll all meet up
at the corner café tonight.
- 我们都会见面
今晚在街角的咖啡馆。
Get ready to party, y'all!
准备好参加派对吧，你们！
- Okay! See you soon!
- Tell her I said, "Hi!"
- 好的！再见！
- 告诉她我说：“嗨！”
- Whoo.
- Tell her I said, "Hi!"
- 呼。
- 告诉她我说：“嗨！”
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Mrs. Puff!
Tell her I said, "Hi!"
- 泡芙夫人！
告诉她我说：“嗨！”
- Yeah!
[both slurping]
- 是的！
[两人都发出咕噜声]
- Ah.
- [computerized noises]
- 啊。
- [电脑噪音]
- [slurping, sighs]
- [吸吮，叹气]
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
Y'all are never gonna believe
what I did this week.
你们永远不会相信
我这周做了什么。
It's about as crazy
as a mule with a top hat.
这同样疯狂
作为一头戴着高礼帽的骡子。
- Was it crazier than this?
"Tell Sandy I said, 'Hi!'
- 还有比这更疯狂的吗？
“告诉桑迪我说，‘嗨！’
Tell Sandy I said 'Hi!'"
告诉桑迪我说‘嗨！’”
[mimics SpongeBob laugh]
[模仿海绵宝宝的笑声]
[sighs]
[叹气]
- Sorry your day
was tough, Puff.
- 对不起你的一天
很难，帕夫。
But my news will cheer
your head off.
但我的消息会让人欢呼
你的头掉下来。
I lived as
a microscopic organism
我的生活是
微观有机体
for a whole week!
整整一个星期！
- That's great, Sandy,
but I've lived
- 太好了，桑迪，
但我曾经活过
with a microscopic organism
for 26 years
与微生物
26年来
and wait until you hear what
that pipsqueak did today.
等到你听到什么
那个小点子今天做了。
He leaves his little telescope
on the floor,
他留下了他的小望远镜
在地板上，
I rolled over it.
It hurt like heck!
我翻过它。
疼得要命！
And then, he gets mad at me
for breaking it.
然后他就生我的气
为了打破它。
Doesn't even ask
if my wheel's okay.
甚至不问
如果我的轮子没问题的话。
- SpongeBob is the same way,
Karen.
- 海绵宝宝也是一样，
凯伦。
After all these years
of my trying to teach him
经过这么多年
我试图教他
how to drive, he doesn't know
the first thing about a car!
怎么开车，他不知道
买车首先要注意的就是！
I'm going crazy!
我要疯了！
[both sob]
[两人都抽泣]
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- 嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿。
We're supposed to be having
a good 'ol time,
我们应该有
美好的时光，
not a good 'ol cry.
不好哭。
- [sniffles]
I'm having a good time.
- [抽鼻子]
我过得很开心。
[wheel creaks]
- Me too.
[车轮吱吱作响]
- 我也是。
- Look, guys.
This is a girls night out.
- 看，伙计们。
这是女孩们的夜晚。
And I'm gonna make sure
we have more fun
我会确定
我们有更多的乐趣
than three rats
in a pickle barrel!
比三只老鼠
在泡菜桶里！
Gal pals unite!
all: Yeah!
姐妹们团结起来！
全体：是啊！
[powering up jingle]
Gal pals!
[通电叮当]
嘎啦朋友们！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- So, let me get
this straight.
- 所以，让我得到
这个直。
Pranking Plankton will
make me feel better?
恶作剧浮游生物会
让我感觉好点吗？
- You bet your sweet software
it will.
- 你用你的甜蜜软件打赌
会的。
Now let's get pranking.
现在我们开始恶作剧吧。
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
- [grunting]
- Whoa.
- [咕哝]
- 哇哦。
- [grunts]
- Whoa, whoa.
- [咕哝]
- 哇哦，哇哦。
both: Whoa!
两人：哇！
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Money, money, money, money,
money, money, money.
- 钱，钱，钱，钱，
钱，钱，钱。
- Ready?
- 准备好？
Yah!
啊！
[glass shatters]
- Ouch!
[玻璃碎裂]
- 哎呀！
Krabs!
螃蟹们！
If I wasn't on probation,
I'd call the cops!
如果我没有处于试用期
我要报警！
- Plank-ter-en,
me old nemisis-ser!
- Plank-ter-en，
我老复仇者爵士！
I've got good news-erer:
我有个好消息——呃：
I'm leaving town and
going back into the "Navery,"
我要离开城镇并且
回到“海军”，
so I'm giving you
me secret formuler-er-rer!
所以我给你
我的秘密配方师！
- What? How do I know
this isn't a trap-erer?
- 什么？我怎么知道
这不是陷阱犯吗？
Ah! You got me doing it.
啊!是你让我这么做的。
- It's a going away gift-erer.
- 这是一个送礼物的人。
[sighs]
[叹气]
I'll get me formuler-er
我会得到我的配方师
out of me safe-er-er-er
从我身边安全呃呃呃
and meet you
at the Krusty Krab-er-er-er.
遇见你
在Krusty Krab-er-er-er。
- I'll meet you there,
Eugene honey!
- 我会在那里见到你
尤金亲爱的！
Mwah! Kiss!
哇！吻！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- I think he bought it.
- 我想他买了。
- Psst! Come on!
- 嘘！快点！
both: Whoa-whoa!
Wha-whoa!
两人：哇哇！
哇哇！
Whoa!
[groans]
哇！
[呻吟]
- [humming happily]
- [高兴地哼哼]
[all giggling]
[大家咯咯地笑]
I'm here!
我在这儿！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[alarm ringing]
[gasps]
[警报响起]
[喘气]
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Plankton!
- 浮游生物！
You've interrupted me
beauty sleep!
你打扰了我
美容觉！
- Hey, Eugene. I'll just
take the secret formuler-erer
- 嘿，尤金。我就
采取秘密配方师
heh and be on my way.
呵呵，上路吧。
- Over my dead body!
- 在我的尸体上！
- Whatever you say, Welcher!
- 无论你说什么，韦尔彻！
[blasting, clattering]
[爆炸声、咔哒声]
[all laughing]
[全都笑了]
- Y'know, you're right, Sandy.
- 你知道，你是对的，桑迪。
I do feel so much better!
我确实感觉好多了！
[powering up jingle]
all: Gal pals!
[通电叮当]
全体：姐妹们！
[explosion]
[爆炸]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- I'm not so sure
about pranking SpongeBob.
- 我不太确定
关于恶作剧海绵宝宝。
He can't help
he's insufferable.
他无能为力
他难以忍受。
- Nobody likes a good prank
more than SpongeBob.
- 没有人喜欢恶作剧
比海绵宝宝还多。
- Mm. Okay.
- 毫米。好的。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- [stifled giggle]
- [压抑的笑声]
[furtive music]
[鬼鬼祟祟的音乐]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- [stifled giggle]
- [压抑的笑声]
Ah!
[grunts]
啊!
[咕哝]
Virtual reality helmet,
engaged.
虚拟现实头盔，
订婚了。
- [murmuring]
- [低语]
[stifled laughter]
[抑制笑声]
[all laughing]
[全都笑了]
- Shh, shh. All right, Karen.
You're up.
- 嘘，嘘。好吧，凯伦。
你起来了。
[stifled laughter]
[抑制笑声]
[doorbell]
- Huh? C-coming!
[门铃]
- 啊？ C-来了！
[groans softly]
[轻声呻吟]
Hello? Can I help you?
你好？我可以帮你吗？
- Hello, Mr. SpongeBob.
- 你好，海绵宝宝先生。
I'm just here to deliver
your driver's license.
我只是来送货的
你的驾驶执照。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
- Oh, uh, thanks--[gasps]
- 哦，呃，谢谢--[喘气]
My driver's license!
我的驾照！
- And your new boat!
- 还有你的新船！
- My new boat!
- 我的新船！
Whoa, wow!
哇哇！
[muttering excitedly]
Am I dreaming?
[兴奋地嘀咕]
我是在做梦吗？
[chirping]
[叽叽喳喳]
[screeches]
[尖叫声]
Nope, it's for real.
不，这是真的。
[cart clanging]
[手推车叮当作响]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Look at me, everyone!
- 大家看着我！
I'm driving!
我在开车！
- Oh! That voice.
- 哦！那个声音。
Yes, you're driving!
You're driving me crazy!
是的，你在开车！
你快把我逼疯了！
[gasps]
[喘气]
[laughs maliciously]
[恶意地笑]
I know! Let's make
the road really bumpy.
我知道！让我们做
路真坎坷。
[straining]
[紧张]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
Wha-what?
Whoa!
什-什么？
哇！
Whoa!
Ow!
哇！
噢！
- [murmurs angrily]
- [愤怒地低语]
- Hm, those are some potholes.
- 嗯，这些是一些坑洼。
- Whoa, girl!
Easy there.
- 哇，女孩！
那里很容易。
Maybe it's about time we let
SpongeBob in on the joke.
也许我们是时候让
海绵宝宝也参与了这个笑话。
- [groans, sputters]
Okay.
- [呻吟，气喘吁吁]
好的。
I'll tell him.
我会告诉他。
SpongeBob--
海绵宝宝——
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
[all scream]
[所有人尖叫]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
Ah.
啊。
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
[wheels squeaking]
[车轮吱吱作响]
- Poor little guy!
- 可怜的小家伙！
This is all my fault!
这都是我的错！
- No, Puff.
This is all my fault.
- 不，泡芙。
这都是我的错。
[powering up jingle]
- Gal pals!
[通电叮当]
- 朋友们！
- Not now, Karen.
- 现在不行，凯伦。
- Sorry.
- 对不起。
[all cheering]
- [laughing]
[大家欢呼]
- [笑]
Ooh, a turn.
Better use my hand signals.
噢，一转。
最好用我的手势。
- SpongeBob! Look out!
[boats approaching]
- 海绵宝宝！当心！
[船只靠近]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
all: Whoa!
全体：哇！
- [laughs] Hi, I'm driving.
- [笑]嗨，我在开车。
Hi, I'm driving.
- Hey!
嗨，我正在开车。
- 嘿！
- Hi, I'm driving!
- 嗨，我在开车！
[laughs]
[笑]
Look, I got a license.
瞧，我拿到了驾照。
[tires screech, explosion]
[轮胎尖叫声、爆炸声]
- Whoa!
- [grunts]
- 哇！
- [咕哝]
- [giggling] Whoo!
- [咯咯笑] 哇！
Nothing but me
and miles of road.
除了我什么都没有
和数英里的道路。
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- We gotta stop this cart,
gal pals.
-我们得停下这辆小车
好朋友们。
[powering up jingle]
[通电叮当]
- [laughing]
[all straining]
- [笑]
[一切都紧张]
- Whoa! Whoa!
- 哇！哇！
I'll save you, SpongeBob!
我会救你的，海绵宝宝！
Whoa! Whoa!
哇！哇！
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Now I'm flying!
Whee!
- 现在我要飞了！
哎哟！
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
- [inflated groan]
- [膨胀的呻吟声]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
Huh? Huh?
Huh.
啊？啊？
呵呵。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
- Huh?
- 啊？
- [sheepish laugh]
- [羞涩的笑声]
- Mrs. Puff?
- 帕夫夫人？
Oh, I see.
我懂了。
You guys played a prank
on me, huh?
你们玩起了恶作剧
在我身上，嗯？
I love pranks!
[laughs]
我喜欢恶作剧！
[笑]
Thank you, thank you,
thank you!
谢谢你，谢谢你，
谢谢！
You gave me a chance
to live my driving dream.
你给了我机会
实现我的驾驶梦想。
And most importantly...
最重要的是...
Mrs. Puff saved my life!
普芙夫人救了我的命！
Now I will stay by your side
forever!
现在我会留在你身边
永远！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- Oh, no!
- 哦，不！
No!
不！
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- [sighs, grunts]
- [叹气，咕哝]
- Huh?
- 啊？
Oh, you girls got me again!
哦，你们这些女孩又抓住了我！
[laughs]
[笑]
[engine revving]
- Vroom!
[发动机转速]
- 弗鲁姆！
Vroom!
[tires screech]
弗鲁姆！
[轮胎尖叫声]
- I know somewhere
where we can finish
- 我知道某个地方
我们可以在哪里完成
our ladies night in peace.
我们的女士们平安夜。
- [laughing] Good one.
- [笑] 很好。
This was a great idea, Sandy.
这是个好主意，桑迪。
- Yeah, what a nice place
to relax.
- 是的，多好的地方啊
放松。
[all slurping]
[全都发出咕噜声]
[all sigh]
[众人叹息]
- Vroom, vroom!
Honk, honk!
- 呜呜呜！
喇叭，喇叭！
Beep, beep!
Oh, look at me, Mrs. Puff!
嘟嘟嘟！
噢，看着我，帕夫太太！
I'm driving!
[laughs]
我在开车！
[笑]
[shouting]
[blows landing]
[喊叫]
[吹着陆]
[both yell]
[两人大喊]
[blow landing, engine revving]
[爆炸着陆，发动机加速]
all: [sigh]
Men.
全体：[叹气]
男人。
[powering up jingle]
Gal pals!
[通电叮当]
嘎啦朋友们！
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
♪ ♪